Guide to the Charles Frederick Chandler Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Professional, 1864-1937
  - Subseries II.2: Academic and Scholarly Activities, 1864-1925
    - Columbia University
      - Chemical Department
        - Investigation into Department, 1898-1899, (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 2 to 3)
        - Reports, 1899-1908 (scattered) (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - College of Pharmacy
        - Certificate in Recognition of Service, 1910 (Box 43, Folder 5)
        - Correspondence, 1887-1924 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      - College of Physicians and Surgeons Correspondence (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - Commencement Addresses- Seth Low, 1895-1902 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - School of Mines
        - Administrative, 1864-1900, (2 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 1 to 2)
        - Correspondence, 1864-1915 (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - Theses advised by Chandler, 1916-1926 (Box 44)
    - Johnson's Encyclopedia Contributions, 1884-1886 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Programs of Scientific Education, 1900-1907 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Public Lectures, 1872-1885 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Union College, 1881, 1918 and undated (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Lab Analyses (5 Boxes) (Box 45-49)
  - Subseries II.3: Municipal Board of Health, 1868-1888
    The Municipal Board of Health Subseries includes files related to Chandler's work with the new York Board of Health. Particularly well-represented in this subseries are Chandler's interests in safe and sanitary tenements and slaughterhouses, though the subseries also includes laboratory analyses of health and beauty products and correspondence files.
    - General, 1868-1883 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Abattoir Plans (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Appointment Certificates, 1873-1884 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Chemical Analyses of Health and Beauty Products (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 1866-1883, (3 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 5 to 7)
    - Correspondence, 1868-1883, (3 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Correspondence- Letterbook, 1882-1884 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Lectures, 1878 and undated, (11 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 1 to 11)
    - Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Reelection Campaign, 1883, (2 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Reports, 1869-1888, (3 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 3 to 5)
    - Tenement Plans (Box 53, Folder 6)
- Series III: Subject Files, Dates
  The Subject File series is comprised of Chandler's own extensive research files and are arranged alphabetically. Many of these files are directly related to chemical, legal, or public health problems that Chandler actively worked on in his career, but there are also many that reflect his general interests in science and technology, such as the files related to photography and photographic processes. A typical subject file may contain clippings and notes, published articles, advertisements, correspondence, and often legal proceedings or legal precedents. As a general rule these are materials collected but not authored by Chandler, exceptions to this will generally be noted. Many of the subject files also contain physical samples of the materials-- notably but certainly not exclusively in Chandler's large collection of dye samples.
  - Adrenaline
    - Correspondence, 1907-1910, (3 Folders) (Box 54, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Notes and Reprints (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Notes and Pamphlets (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 54, Folder 6 to 7)
  - Agriculture
    - Articles and Clippings, (2 Folders) (Box 55, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Articles (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Clippings (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1900-1907 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Notes and Lectures, (2 Folders) (Box 56, Folder 5 to 6)
  - Air Ventilation and Heating
    - Advertisements, (2 Folders) (Box 57, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Boilers, (2 Folders) (Box 57, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Boiler Case Notes, 1904 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 58, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Correspondence, 1879-1908 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Notes and Resources (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Clippings and Articles, (6 Folders) (Box 59, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 60, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Heating Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 60, Folder 3 to 5)
    - Heating Notes (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Lectures on Heating-Notes and Resources (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Notes for Lecture on Atmosphere and Ventilation, (2 Folders) (Box 61, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Patents (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Alcohol
    - Advertisements and Price Lists (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Clippings and Pamphlets (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1858-1920, (2 Folders) (Box 62, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Undated Correspondence, Telegrams, and Misc. (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - CFC Lecture on Beer (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - CFC vs. Harry Read-Injunction, 1873 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Legal Documents (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Notes and Clippings, (3 Folders) (Box 63, Folder 4 to 6)
    - Notes and Clippings, (4 Folders) (Box 64, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Pamphlets, (4 Folders) (Box 65, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Pamphlets (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Articles and Pamphlets (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Reprints (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Books and Pamphlets (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Pamphlets, (2 Folders) (Box 67, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Patent Specifications (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Alkaloids
    - Alkalis (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Drugs, General
      - Articles, (3 Folders) (Box 68, Folder 2 to 4)
      - Chinoline (Box 68, Folder 5)
      - Clipping and Notes (Box 68, Folder 6)
      - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 69, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Correspondence, 1858-1900 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Advertisements (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Caffeine-Bromo Caffeine Case, 1881-1892 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Cocaine-Coca-Cola Case (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Opium
      - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 70, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Correspondence, 1874-1888 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Tea
      - Clippings (Box 70, Folder 4)
      - 1883 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Tobacco-Kinney Tobacco Case
      - Notes, 1889 (Box 71, Folder 2)
      - 1889 (Box 71, Folder 3)
      - Clippings (Box 71, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 1889-1891 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Alloys (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Aluminum
    - Advertisements and Price Lists, (2 Folders) (Box 72, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Clippings, (3 Folders) (Box 72, Folder 3 to 5)
    - Clippings and Articles (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Clippings, (5 Folders) (Box 73, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Clippings and Articles (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Clippings and Articles, (5 Folders) (Box 74, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Clippings (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Clippings (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - 1880-1916, (2 Folders) (Box 75, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Pittsburgh Reduction Company Case, 1891-1893 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Bradley Case-Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 75, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Bradley Case- Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 76, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Hall Process
      - Charles M. Hall (Box 76, Folder 3)
      - Patent Cases (Box 76, Folder 4)
      - Patent Case-Chandler’s Notes, 1898, (3 Folders) (Folder 5 to 7)
        - 1891-1899, undated, (4 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Patent Specifications, (2 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Patent Specifications, (2 Folders) (Box 78, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Photographs (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Pittsburgh Reduction Company v. The Electric Smelting and Aluminum Company-Legal Documents (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Pittsburgh Reduction Company v. Cowles Electric Smelting and Aluminum Company-Legal Documents, 1891 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Pittsburgh Reduction Company Case
      - Legal Documents, (4 Folders) (Box 79, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Antimony (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - Arsenic
    - In Wallpaper
      - Arsenical Wallpaper Samples (Box 82)
      - Correspondence, 1874-1906, (2 Folders) (Box 80, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Clippings and Articles (Box 80, Folder 3)
      - Notes (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - In Medicine (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Clippings and Articles, (3 Folders) (Box 80, Folder 6 to 8)
    - Clippings and Articles, (4 Folders) (Box 81, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Clippings and Articles, (2 Folders) (Box 83, Folder 1 to 2)
    - In Air-Notes (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Clippings-Stephen’s Murder Case, 1859 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Legal Documents (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Ash-Leaches (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Atomic Weights (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Batteries and Electrochemistry
    - Advertisements (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Articles, (4 Folders) (Box 84, Folder 2 to 5)
    - Articles, (3 Folders) (Box 85, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 85, Folder 4 to 6)
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 86, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Correspondence, 1889-1907 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Lectures, (2 Folders) (Box 86, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Lectures- Niagara Falls, 1901-1908, (2 Folders) (Box 87, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 87, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Patents, (2 Folders) (Box 87, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Patents, (6 Folders) (Box 88, Folder 1 to 6)
  - Bromine- Patents (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Boron and Borax (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Borated Cotton Case, 1889 (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Butter and Oleomargarine
    - Articles and Publications, (5 Folders) (Box 89, Folder 1 to 5)
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 89, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Chemical Analyses (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1873-1902, (2 Folders) (Box 90, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Dealers (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - Legal Cases, 1870-1886 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 90, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Paraff, Alfred Oleomargarine Fraud, 1877 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Patent Specifications, 1874-1878 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - Photographic Plates (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Calcium Carbide (Acetylene)
    - Advertisements (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Articles, (3 Folders) (Box 91, Folder 2 to 4)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 92, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Correspondence, 1894-1909 (Box 92, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Ethene (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Legal Documents (Box 93, Folder 1)
    - Legal Case Notes, 1902 (Box 93, Folder 2)
    - Patents, (2 Folders) (Box 93, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Photographs (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Camphor (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Carbon and Carbonation
    - American Carbonate Co. Case, 1897 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Articles, (3 Folders) (Box 94, Folder 2 to 4)
    - Carbon Dioxide-- Patents (Box 94, Folder 5)
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 94, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Correspondence, 1860-1900 (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Cement and Stone
    - Advertisements (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Articles, (6 Folders) (Box 95, Folder 2 to 7)
    - Buddensick's Mortar Case, 1885 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Calcium Lecture Notes (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Clippings and Notes, (4 Folders) (Box 96, Folder 3 to 6)
    - Correspondence, 1860-1903, (2 Folders) (Box 96, Folder 7 to 8)
  - Ceramics
    - Advertisements, (2 Folders) (Box 97, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Article on Hard Porcelain (Draft) (Box 97, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1870-1917 (Box 97, Folder 4)
    - History of
      - Articles, (2 Folders) (Box 97, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Articles, (3 Folders) (Box 98, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 98, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 99, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Legal Cases-- Terra Cotta Case, Notes, 1894 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - Legal Documents (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Patents (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Cheese, (3 Folders) (Box 100, Folder 1 to 3)
  - Chemical History
    - Articles (Box 100, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Clippings and Notes, (4 Folders) (Box 101, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Lectures and Notes (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - Publications (Box 102)
    - Publications, (2 Folders) (Box 103, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Wohler, Frederick (Box 103, Folder 3)
  - Chemical Philosophy (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - Chlorine
    - General (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Patents (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Chloroform
    - General (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1886-1887 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Legal Cases-- Notes, 1886 (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 104, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 105, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Notes (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Copper
    - Articles (Box 106)
    - Articles (Box 107, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 107, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Correspondence, 1867-1911 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - Corn Syrup
    - Correspondence, 1901-1913, (2 Folders) (Box 107, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Legal Case Notes, 1919, (3 Folders) (Box 108, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Legal Documents, 1911 (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - Notes and Clippings (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Dyes and Dyeing
    - Alizarine
      - Articles, (3 Folders) (Box 109, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 109, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Clippings and Notes, (5 Folders) (Box 110, Folder 1 to 5)
      - Correspondence, 1875-1884 (Box 110, Folder 6)
      - Lecture Notes (Box 111, Folder 1)
      - Legal Documents
        - General (Box 111, Folder 2)
        - Alizarine Assistant Case, 1868-1869, (4 Folders) (Box 111, Folder 3 to 6)
      - Notes (Box 112, Folder 1)
      - Patents, (2 Folders) (Box 112, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Samples (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - Aniline Dyes
      - A2O Dyes (Box 113, Folder 2)
      - Acid Fuchsia (Box 113, Folder 3)
      - Aniline Black Case, 1899 (Box 113, Folder 4)
      - Aniline Black Samples, 1910-1911 (Levinstein) (Box 113, Folder 5)
      - "Aniline Color" Article and Notes (Box 113, Folder 6)
      - Aniline Red - Clippings and Notes (Box 114, Folder 1)
      - Aniline Yellow- Legal Case, 1882-1884, (2 Folders) (Box 114, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 114, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Clippings and Notes, (5 Folders) (Box 115, Folder 1 to 5)
      - Samples (Box 115, Folder 6)
    - Articles (Box 116-117)
    - Benzo-Purpine
      - Correspondence, 1889-1896 (Box 118, Folder 1)
      - Legal Documents, (5 Folders) (Box 118, Folder 2 to 6)
      - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 119, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 119, Folder 3 to 5)
    - Calico Printing
      - Clippings and Notes, (4 Folders) (Box 120, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Classification Systems, (2 Folders) (Box 120, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Clippings and Notes, (5 Folders) (Box 121-124)
    - Clippings and Notes-- Natural Dyes (Box 125)
    - Clippings and Notes-- Natural Dyes, (2 Folders) (Box 126, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Correspondence, 1872-1916, (3 Folders) (Box 126, Folder 3 to 5)
    - Correspondence, 1872-1916, (2 Folders) (Box 127, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Dye Industry
      - Advertisements and Clippings, (5 Folders) (Box 127, Folder 3 to 7)
    - Indigo
      - Articles, (2 Folders) (Box 128, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Clippings and Notes (Box 128, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence, 1898-1899 (Box 128, Folder 4)
      - Encyclopedia Article Drafts and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 128, Folder 5 to 7)
      - Lecture Notes (Box 129, Folder 1)
      - Legal Case Notes (Box 129, Folder 2)
      - Samples (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - Lecture Notes
      - Anthracen Colors (Box 129, Folder 4)
      - Coloring Matters (Box 129, Folder 5)
      - Lichen Dyes (Box 129, Folder 6)
      - Naphthol (Box 129, Folder 7)
      - Relation of Color to Composition (Box 129, Folder 8)
      - Vegetable Dyestuffs (Box 129, Folder 9)
    - Legal Cases
      - Black Dye Cases
        - Aniline Black, Notes (Box 130, Folder 1)
        - Correspondence, 1910-1911 (Box 130, Folder 2)
        - Diamin Black Case, 1893 (Box 130, Folder 3)
        - Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 130, Folder 4 to 6)
        - Patent Specifications and Legal Documents (Box 130, Folder 7)
      - Logwood Case, 1890, (3 Folders) (Box 131, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Methylene Blue Case, (3 Folders) (Box 131, Folder 4 to 6)
      - Naphthol Black, 1892 (Box 132, Folder 1)
      - Oakes Mordanting Case, 1898 (Box 132, Folder 2)
      - Pellew v. Susquehanna Dye Works, (2 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Legal Documents, (3 Folders) (Box 132, Folder 5 to 7)
    - Legal Documents (Box 133)
    - Madder
      - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 134, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Lecture Notes (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Mercerizing
      - Articles (Box 134, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence, 1900-1904 (Box 135, Folder 1)
      - Legal Cases, (4 Folders) (Box 135, Folder 2 to 5)
      - Legal Cases (Box 136-137)
      - Legal Documents (Box 138, Folder 1)
      - Case Notes, 1902 (Box 138, Folder 2)
      - Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 138, Folder 3 to 4)
      - Patents, (2 Folders) (Box 139, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Publications (Box 139, Folder 3)
      - Samples of Mercerized Fabric (Box 139, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Samples of Mercerized Fabric (Box 140)
    - Mordant (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - Patents, (4 Folders) (Box 141, Folder 2 to 5)
    - Perkin's Mauve (Box 141, Folder 6)
    - Phenol Dyes (Box 141, Folder 7)
    - Saffranin (Box 141, Folder 8)
    - Samples (Box 142-143)
  - Electricity
    - General (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - Advertisements (Box 144, Folder 2)
    - Arc Lamps
      - Ads (Box 144, Folder 3)
      - Clippings and Notes, (4 Folders) (Box 144, Folder 4 to 7)
    - Articles (Box 145)
    - Atmospheric Electricity (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 146, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Correspondence, 1875-1909, (2 Folders) (Box 146, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Dynamical Electricity, (4 Folders) (Box 147, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Electrical Lighting
      - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 147, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 148, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Lecture Notes (Box 148, Folder 4)
    - Electrical Machines-- Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 148, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Electrical Measurements (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Electrolytic Apparatus Patents, (2 Folders) (Box 149, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Lamps, (2 Folders) (Box 149, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Legal Case Notes (Box 149, Folder 6)
    - Legal Case Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 150, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 150, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Legal Documents (Box 151)
    - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 152, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Medical Uses of Electricity, (2 Folders) (Box 152, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Patents (Box 152, Folder 5)
    - Lecture Notes of Lecture Notes (Box 153, Folder 1)
    - Notes (Box 153, Folder 2)
    - Popular Lecture on Electricity (Box 153, Folder 3)
    - Statical Electricity, (2 Folders) (Box 153, Folder 4 to 5)
  - Elevated Railroad
    - General, 1884-1911 (Box 154, Folder 1)
    - Blueprints and Photographs (Box 154, Folder 2)
    - Case Notes, 1884 (Box 154, Folder 3)
    - Legal Documents, 1884 (Box 154, Folder 4)
  - Explosives
    - Advertisements (Box 155, Folder 1)
    - Analyses (Box 155, Folder 2)
    - Articles and Publications, (5 Folders) (Box 155, Folder 3 to 7)
    - Brooklyn Institute Explosives, 1916-1918 (Box 156, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and Notes, (4 Folders) (Box 156, Folder 2 to 5)
    - Correspondence, 1869-1915 (Box 156, Folder 6)
    - Dynamite- Notes (Box 157, Folder 1)
    - Gunpowder- Glued to Wax Paper, Item removed from collection- please refer to digital image
    - Gunpowder- Packets of Gunpowder Samples, Item removed from collection- please refer to digital image
    - Notebooks, 1880 (Box 157, Folder 2)
    - Oleum Drum Case, 1916-1917, (2 Folders) (Box 157, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Patents (Box 157, Folder 5)
    - Smokeless Powder Article (Box 157, Folder 6)
  - Fertilizer
    - Articles, (2 Folders) (Box 158, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Advertisements, (2 Folders) (Box 158, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 158, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Correspondence, 1866-1897, (2 Folders) (Box 159, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 159, Folder 3 to 4)
  - Fire
    - Advertisements (Box 160, Folder 1)
    - Articles, (4 Folders) (Box 160, Folder 2 to 5)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 161)
    - Combustion Lecture, (2 Folders) (Box 162, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Correspondence, 1872-1908 (Box 162, Folder 3)
    - Fireproofing Case, 1906 (Box 162, Folder 4)
    - Fireproofing Patents (Box 162, Folder 5)
  - Food
    - Advertisements (Box 163, Folder 1)
    - Articles and Publications, (5 Folders) (Box 163, Folder 2 to 6)
    - Articles and Publications, (3 Folders) (Box 164, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Notes (Box 164, Folder 4)
    - Adulteration
      - Clippings and Notes (Box 164, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence (Box 164, Folder 6)
      - Articles, General (Box 165, Folder 1)
      - House of Commons Report on Food Adulteration, 1856 (Box 165, Folder 2)
      - Board of Health Correspondence, 1868-1869 (Box 165, Folder 3)
      - Board of Health Analyses and Report, 1868-1883 (Box 165, Folder 4)
      - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 165, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Baking Powder (Box 165)
      - General (Box 166, Folder 1)
      - Baking Powder Adulteration, 1878-1889, (2 Folders) (Box 166, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Horsford Case, 1870s, (4 Folders) (Box 166, Folder 4 to 7)
      - Horsford Case, 1870s, (2 Folders) (Box 167, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Baking Soda (Box 167, Folder 3)
    - Cereals-- American Middlings Purifier Co. Case, 1899 (Box 167, Folder 4)
    - Meat Juice
      - Clippings and Notes (Box 167, Folder 5)
      - Legal Documents (Box 167, Folder 6)
    - Swine Commission, 1884 (Box 167, Folder 7)
  - Furnaces
    - General (Box 168, Folder 1)
    - Doherty Case, 1905 (Box 168, Folder 2)
  - Gas
    - Articles, (3 Folders) (Box 168, Folder 3 to 5)
    - Articles, (2 Folders) (Box 169, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Clippings and Notes, (3 Folders) (Box 169, Folder 3 to 5)
    - Clippings and Notes, (4 Folders) (Box 170, Folder 1 to 4)
    - Coal Gas, (3 Folders) (Box 170, Folder 5 to 7)
    - Coal Gas, (2 Folders) (Box 171, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Correspondence, 1865-1910, (3 Folders) (Box 171, Folder 3 to 5)
    - Fittings, Burners, and Meters, (2 Folders) (Box 172, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Government Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 172, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Legal Documents, (2 Folders) (Box 172, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Lighting
      - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 173, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Lectures, 1870-1875 (Box 173, Folder 3)
      - Manuscript on Gas Lighting (Box 173, Folder 4)
    - Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 173, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 174, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Patent Specifications (Box 174, Folder 3)
    - Welsbach Mantle Case
      - Advertisements (Box 174, Folder 4)
      - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 174, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Clippings and Notes, (4 Folders) (Box 175, Folder 1 to 4)
      - Correspondence, 1888-1908, (2 Folders) (Box 175, Folder 5 to 6)
      - Legal Documents (Box 176-177)
  - Geology, Mining, and Metallurgy
    - American Bureau of Mines Reports and Notes, 1866 (Box 178, Folder 1)
    - Articles and Publications, (4 Folders) (Box 178, Folder 2 to 5)
    - Articles and Publications, (2 Folders) (Box 179, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Articles- by J.Kemp (Box 179, Folder 3)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 179, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1862-1900 (Box 179, Folder 5)
    - Lecture Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 179, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Legal Cases (Box 180, Folder 1)
      - Case Notes, 1911 (Box 180, Folder 2)
      - Ajax Metal Case, 1903-1907, (2 Folders) (Box 180, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Maps (Box 180, Folder 5)
  - Glass
    - Advertisements (Box 180, Folder 6)
    - Articles (Box 180, Folder 7)
    - Articles (Box 181, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and Notes, (2 Folders) (Box 181, Folder 2 to 3)
    - Correspondence, 1901 (Box 181, Folder 4)
    - Wire Glass (Box 181, Folder 5)
  - Glucose
    - Articles, (2 Folders) (Box 181, Folder 6 to 7)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 181, Folder 8)
    - Clippings and Notes (Box 182)